Register of the Milton Friedman papers 77011.4088897
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1933-1982 (Boxes 36-74)
  - A Monetary History of the United States, 1867-1960 (1963)
    - Typescript
      - Final version (chapters 3-7) (Box-folder 47: 7)
    - Charts (Box-folder 47: 8)
    - Comments (Box-folder 47: 9)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 47: 10)
    - Reply to James Tobin [See also: Correspondence] (Box-folder 47: 11)
    - Correspondence with Anna J. Schwartz, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 47: 12)
  - "Money and Business Cycles" (with Anna J. Schwartz)," Review of Economics and Statistics, holograph, 1963 February (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - "Exchange Rate Policy," Swarajya, printed copy, 1963 March 30 (Box-folder 48: 2)
    Includes reprint by Forum of Free Enterprise under the title "India Needs a Free Market Exchange Rate," and correspondence with M. R. Pai.
  - "Indian Economic Planning" (1963 May 6)
    - Research material (Box-folder 48: 3)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - Correspondence and comments (Box-folder 48: 5)
  - "Price Determination in the U.S. Treasury Bill Market: A Comment," Review of Economics and Statistics, correspondence, 1963 August (Box-folder 48: 6)
  - "What Part Should Japan Play in the World Economy?," Nihon Keizai Shimbun (Japan Economic Journal), typescript and correspondence, 1963 November (Box-folder 48: 7)
  - Review of Dwight D. Murphey, Emergent Man, typescript, 1964 (Box-folder 48: 8)
  - "Planning Versus Progress Around the World," speech, Employers' Association of the Milwaukee, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, holograph and typescript summary, 1964 March (Box-folder 48: 9)
  - "Note on Lag in Effect of Monetary Policy," typescript and letter to John G. Gurley (American Economic Review), 1964 May 8 (Box-folder 48: 10)
  - Letter to the editor regarding Ben B. Seligman, "The Search for a Working Theory," Challenge, typescript, 1964 May 21 (Box-folder 48: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, Wall Street Journal, typescript, 1964 July 2 (Box-folder 48: 12)
  - Speech on general economic policy, typescript draft, 1964 August 26 (Box-folder 48: 13)
  - "Computation of H, D/C, D/R, and Source of Data," research material and typescript, 1965 (Box-folder 48: 14)
  - "Responsibility: Insights from Economics," discussion with Paul S. Russell and Wesley Clair Mitchell, Institute for Religious and Social Studies, New York City, typescript, 1965 March 8 (Box-folder 48: 15)
  - "Reply to Ando and Modigliani and to DePrano and Mayer" (with David Meiselman), American Economic Review, typescript and correspondence, 1965 September (Box-folder 48: 16)
  - "The Political Economy of International Monetary Arrangements," speech, Mont Pélerin Society, Stresa, Italy, typescript, 1965 September 7 (Box-folder 48: 17)
  - "The Lessons of U.S. Monetary History and Their Bearing on Current Policy," memorandum, Consultants Meeting, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, typescript, 1965 October 7 (Box-folder 48: 18)
  - "Free-Market Determination of Exchange Rates,", 1966? (Box-folder 48: 19)
    Based on statement, United States, Congress, Joint Economic Committee, Subcommittee on International Exchange and Payments, 1966. Annotated copy of statement printed in Contingency Planning for U.S. International Monetary Policy, 1966.
  - The Minimum Wage: Who Pays? (with Yale Brozen), printed copy, 1966 April (Box-folder 48: 20)
  - "Minimum Wage Rates and Unemployment," Newsweek, holograph and typescript, 1966 September 11 (Box-folder 48: 21)
  - "Interest Rates and the Demand for Money," Journal of Law and Economics, typescript, 1966 October (Box-folder 48: 22)
  - "Trends in Money, Income, and Prices, 1867-1966" (with Anna J. Schwartz) (1966 November)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 49: 1-2)
    - Charts (Box-folder 49: 3)
    - Correspondence and comments (Box-folder 49: 4)
  - "The Case for the Negative Income Tax: A View from the Right," speech, National Symposium on Guaranteed Income, United States Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C., notes and printed copy, 1966 December 9 (Box-folder 49: 5)
  - Series of speeches on money, University of California, Los Angeles, California, typescript, 1967 January (Box-folder 49: 6)
  - "The Case for Free Rates," participation with Robert V. Roosa, Rational Debate Seminar, American Enterprise Institute, Washington, D.C., typescript, rebuttal, and correspondence with Robert A. Mundell, 1967 May 18 (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - "Can Governments Guarantee Everyone an Annual Income?," speech, Illinois State Chamber of Commerce Symposium, holograph summary, 1967 October 26 (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - "Strong Dollar Seen in Free Markets" (with William Fellner, Harry G. Johnson, Fritz Machlup), letter to the editor, New York Times, printed copy, 1967 November 26 (Box-folder 49: 9)
  - "The Role of Monetary Policy," speech, American Economic Association, Washington, D.C., typescript (1967 December 29)
    - First draft, entitled "Can Full Employment Be a Criterion of Monetary Policy?" (Box-folder 49: 10)
    - Final version (Box-folder 49: 11)
  - Dollars and Deficits: Inflation, Monetary Policy and the Balance of Payments, 1968 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    Typescript of epilogue for the French translation, 1969.
  - "The Market Versus the Bureaucrat," paper, Individuality and the New Society Symposium, Reed College, Portland, Oregon, typescript, 1968 March 16 (Box-folder 50: 2)
  - The Optimum Quantity of Money and Other Essays (1969)
    - Typescript of "The Optimum Quantity of Money" (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - Proofs (Box-folder 50: 4-6)
    - Correspondence and comments, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 50: 7)
    - Reviews, 1970 (Box-folder 50: 8)
      Includes correspondence with American Institute for Economic Research.
  - "The Definition of Money: Net Wealth and Neutrality as Criteria" (with Anna J. Schwartz), Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, typescript, 1969 February (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - "The Euro-Dollar Market: Some First Principles," Morgan Guarantee Survey (1969 October)
    - Research material (Box-folder 51: 2)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 51: 3)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 51: 4)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Monetary Statistics of the United States (with Anna J. Schwartz) (1970)
    - Research material (Box-folder 51: 6)
    - Charts and tables (Box-folder 51: 7-9)
      Includes notes and correspondence with Anna J. Schwartz.
    - Notes (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - Holograph outline (Box-folder 52: 2)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 52: 3-12)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1969
      - General (Box-folder 52: 13)
      - Schwartz, Anna J. (Box-folder 52: 14)
  - "Controls on Interest Rates Paid by Banks," Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, typescript, 1970 February (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - "A Theoretical Framework for Monetary Analysis," Journal of Political Economy (1970 March-April)
    - General (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 53: 3-5)
  - "Comment on Tobin," Quarterly Journal of Economics, typescript, 1970 May (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - Memorandum, Consultants Meeting, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, typescript (partial), 1970 June 19 (Box-folder 53: 7)
  - "The Proof of the Monetarist Pudding," typescript, 1970 July 1 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - "A Monetary Theory of Nominal Income," Journal of Political Economy, 1971 March-April (Box-folder 53: 9)
    Notes, typescript, and comments, 1970.
  - "Social Security: Universal or Selective," participation with Wilbur J. Cohen, Rational Debate Seminar, American Enterprise Seminar, Washington, D.C., typescript, 1971 April 28 (Box-folder 53: 10)
  - "Government Revenue from Inflation," Journal of Political Economy (1971 July-August)
    - Notes and holograph (Box-folder 53: 11)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 53: 12)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 53: 13)
  - "Monetary Policy," speech, Symposium on Achieving Our Economic Objectives Under the Employment Act of 1946, American Philosophical Society, typescript, 1971 November 12 (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - "Have Monetary Policies Failed?," paper, American Economic Association (1971 December 28)
    - Research material, charts, and notes (Box-folder 54: 2)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 54: 3)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 54: 4)
    - Correspondence, including with Anna J. Schwartz (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - "Comments on the Critics," Journal of Political Economy Symposium (1972 September/October)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 54: 6)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 54: 7)
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 54: 8)
    - Contributions by others (Box-folder 54: 9)
    - Correspondence with Robert J. Gordon (Journal of Political Economy), Allan H. Meltzer, Don Patinkin, James Tobin, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 54: 10)
    - Version reprinted in Robert J. Gordon, ed., Milton's Friedman Monetary Framework: A Debate With His Critics (1974)
      - General (Box-folder 55: 1)
      - Introduction by Robert J. Gordon and correspondence between him and others, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 55: 2)
      - Correspondence with Don Patinkin, 1974 (Box-folder 55: 3)
      - Comments by Anna J. Schwartz, 1977 (Box-folder 55: 4)
      - Reviews (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - "Contemporary Monetary Problems," speech, National Bank of Yugoslavia, Belgrade, Yugoslavia, typescript, 1973 March 20 (Box-folder 55: 6)
  - "Money," Encyclopedia Britannica, typescript, 1974 (Box-folder 55: 7)
  - "Schools at Chicago," speech, 54th Annual Board of Trustees' Dinner for the Faculty, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, printed copy, 1974 January 9 (Box-folder 55: 8)
  - "Statement on Indexing as a Tool for Economic Stabilization," United States, Congress, House of Representatives, Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, Subcommittee on Production and Stabilization, typescript and cover letter, 1974 June 3 (Box-folder 55: 9)
  - "Using Escalators to Help Fight Inflation," Fortune (1974 July)
    - Holograph (Box-folder 55: 10)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 55: 11)
    - Expanded version in Inflation: Causes, Consequences, Cures, (Institute of Economic Affairs Readings, No. 14), entitled "Inflation, Taxation, Indexation," correspondence with and preface by Arthur Seldon, 1974 (Box-folder 55: 12)
  - "Inflation Is Created By Government and By No One Else," participation in discussion moderated by Andrew Shonfield, Royal Institution, London, England, typed transcript of British Broadcasting Corporation radio broadcast, 1974 September 23 (Box-folder 55: 13)
  - "Myth and Reality in Contemporary Public Opinion," typescript outline, 1974 December 6 (Box-folder 55: 14)
  - "The Future of Capitalism," Student Conference on National Affairs XX Proceedings, printed copy, 1975 (Box-folder 55: 15)
  - There's No Such Thing as a Free Lunch, blurb and reviews, 1975 (Box-folder 55: 16)
  - Unemployment Versus Inflation? An Evaluation of the Phillips Curve, (Institute of Economic Affairs Occasional Paper. No. 44), proofs, 1975 (Box-folder 55: 17)
  - "The Future of the American Economy," Bicentennial Lecture, American Experience Program, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1976 February 5 (Box-folder 55: 18)
  - "Adam Smith's Wealth of Nations: Is There a Future for Laissez-Faire?," participation, Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars Evening Dialogue, Washington, D.C., program, notes, and holograph outline, 1976 April 14 (Box-folder 55: 19)
  - "Economics and Social Progress: Adam Smith Plus 200 Years," speech, Tuck 75th Anniversary Symposium, holograph, 1976 May 28 (Box-folder 55: 20)
  - "Adam Smith's Relevance for 1976," speech, Mont Pélerin Society, St. Andrews, Scotland, holograph and typescript, 1976 August 27 (Box-folder 55: 21)
  - "Homer Jones: A Personal Reminiscence," Journal of Monetary Economics, typescript, 1976 November (Box-folder 55: 22)
  - "Inflation and Unemployment," Nobel Lecture, Stockholm, Sweden (1976 December 10)
    - General (Box-folder 55: 23)
    - Typescript and printed copy (Box-folder 55: 24)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 55: 25-26)
  - "The Future of Capitalism," speech, Sweden, typescript, 1977-1980? (Box-folder 55: 27)
  - "The Source of Strength," speech, President's Club of Michigan General Corporation, New Orleans, Louisiana, printed copy, 1977 April 2 (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - "Fair Versus Free," commencement address, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Virginia, typescript, 1977 May 28 (Box-folder 56: 2)
  - Commencement address, Hebrew University, Jerusalem, typescript, 1977 July 4 (Box-folder 56: 3)
  - "Who Protects the Consumer?," speech, Pfizer Employees Nonpartisan Good Government Fund, New York City, typescript outline and printed copy of condensed version, 1977 September 12 (Box-folder 56: 4)
  - "Putting Learning Back in the Classroom," speech, Harlem, New York, outline and edited typed transcript, 1977 September 15 (Box-folder 56: 5)
  - "Who Protects the Worker?," speech, Erie, Pennsylvania, holograph and typescript outline, 1977 September 29 (Box-folder 56: 6)
  - "What Is America?," speech, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois. holograph and typescript outline, 1977 October 3 (Box-folder 56: 7)
  - "Myths that Conceal Reality," Ninth George S. Eccles Distinguished Lecture, Utah State University, Logan, Utah, typescript (partial), 1977 October 12 (Box-folder 56: 8)
  - "Von Mises, the Man," New American Review, review of Margit von Mises, My Years with Ludwig von Mises, typescript, 1977 November (Box-folder 56: 9)
  - "The Economics of Free Speech," speech, University of San Diego, San Diego, California, typescript outline and proofs, 1977 November 7 (Box-folder 56: 10)
  - "Money and Inflation," speech, San Diego, California, typescript outline, 1977 November 7 (Box-folder 56: 11)
  - "The Economy and You: What Lies Ahead?," Stanford Magazine, typescript, 1977-1978 Fall/Winter (Box-folder 56: 12)
  - "The Energy Crisis: A Humane Solution," research material, notes, typescript, and printed copy, 1978 (Box-folder 56: 13)
  - "Is Tax Reform Possible?," speech, American Educational League, Pasadena, California, typescript outline, 1978 February 6 (Box-folder 56: 14)
  - "The Role of Government in a Free Society," speech, Stanford University, Stanford, California, typescript outline, 1978 February 9 (Box-folder 56: 15)
  - "Energy," speech, San Francisco, California, typescript outline, 1978 February 10 (Box-folder 56: 16)
  - "The Future of Our Free Society," speech (afternoon), National Association of Manufacturers, Washington, D.C., typescript outline, 1978 February 21 (Box-folder 56: 17)
  - "The Future of Our Free Society," remarks and discussion (evening), Conversation Series, American Enterprise Institute, Washington, D.C., edited typed transcript, 1978 February 21 (Box-folder 56: 18)
  - "What's Wrong With the Welfare System?," speech, Roberts Wesleyan College, Rochester, New York, holograph outline, 1978 February 23 (Box-folder 56: 19)
  - "Has the Tide Turned?," Hoover Foundation Inaugural Lecture, Strathclyde University Business School, Glasgow, Scotland, typescript outline and transcript of British Broadcasting Corporation radio broadcast, 1978 April 21 (Box-folder 56: 20)
    Includes cover letters.
  - "Free Trade: Producer Versus Consumer," speech, Kansas State University of Agriculture and Applied Science, Manhattan, Kansas, typescript outline, 1978 April 27 (Box-folder 56: 21)
  - "Equality and Freedom," speech, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, typescript outline, 1978 May 1 (Box-folder 56: 22)
  - "Can Leviathan Be Halted?," speech, Economic Club, Detroit, Michigan, printed copy, 1978 May 18 (Box-folder 56: 23)
  - "The Economics of Medical Care," speech, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, typescript outline, 1978 May 19. (Box-folder 56: 24)
  - "The Limitations of Tax Limitation," Policy Review, printed copy, 1978 Summer (Box-folder 56: 25)
  - "The Pound and Dollar Over a Century," Harry G. Johnson Memorial Lecture, Royal Society, London, England (1979 April 9)
    - Research material (Box-folder 56: 26)
    - Holograph outline and typescript (Box-folder 56: 27)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 56: 28)
  - Free to Choose (with Rose D. Friedman) (1980)
    - Research material
      - General (Box-folder 56: 29)
      - Chapter 1 (Box-folder 56: 30-31)
      - Chapter 2 (Box-folder 56: 32)
      - Chapter 3 (Box-folder 56: 33)
      - Chapter 4 (Box-folder 56: 34-35)
      - Chapter 5 (Box-folder 57: 1)
      - Chapter 6 (Box-folder 57: 2-3)
      - Chapter 7 (Box-folder 57: 4)
      - Chapter 8 (Box-folder 57: 5, 58: 1)
      - Chapter 9 (Box-folder 58: 2)
    - Notes
      - General (Box-folder 58: 3)
      - Chapter 4 (Box-folder 58: 4)
      - Chapter 6 (Box-folder 58: 5-6)
      - Chapter 7 (Box-folder 58: 7)
      - Chapter 8 (Box-folder 58: 8-9)
      - Chapter 9 (Box-folder 58: 10)
      - Chapter 10 (Box-folder 58: 11)
    - Holograph
      - Chapter 1 (Box-folder 58: 12)
      - Chapter 6 (Box-folder 58: 13)
      - Chapter 7 (Box-folder 58: 14)
      - Chapter 8 (Box-folder 58: 15)
      - Chapter 10 (Box-folder 58: 16)
    - Typescript
      - Unidentified
        - Blurb (Box-folder 59: 1)
        - Loose pages (Box-folder 59: 2)
      - Discarded draft (partial) (Box-folder 59: 3-4)
      - First draft (Box-folder 59: 5-11)
      - Second draft
        - Preface (Box-folder 59: 12)
        - Introduction (Box-folder 59: 13)
      - Revised second draft (Box-folder 60: 1-3)
    - Proofs (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Box-folder 61: 2-3)
      - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc., 1979 (Box-folder 61: 4)
    - List of topics for Milton Friedman's lecture series "Capitalism and Freedom" for Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc. (Box-folder 61: 5)
      Includes typescript outline of first lecture.
  - Free to Choose, public television series of ten one-hour programs (1980 January 11, date of first airing)
    - General (Box-folder 61: 6)
    - Notes (Box-folder 61: 7)
    - Typed script
      - Opening and closing statements and introduction (Box-folder 61: 8)
      - Programs 1-10 (Box-folder 61: 9)
      - Program 4 (Box-folder 61: 10)
      - Program 6 (Box-folder 61: 11)
      - Program 10 (Box-folder 61: 12)
    - Supplementary curriculum materials for high school teachers (Box-folder 61: 13)
  - Memorandum to U.K. Treasury and Civil Service Committee regarding "Enquiry Into Monetary Policy," United Kingdom, House of Commons, typescript, 1980 July (Box-folder 61: 14)
  - Monetary Trends in the United States and the United Kingdom (with Anna J. Schwartz) (1982)
    - Research material, charts, graphs, and tables (Boxes 62-64)
      Includes correspondence with Anna J. Schwartz.
    - Holograph and typescript
      Includes research material, charts, graphs, tables, notes, and correspondence with Anna J. Schwartz and others.
      - Chapters 2-6, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 65: 1-11)
      - Chapters 6-9, 1973 (Box-folder 66: 1-4)
      - Chapters 5 and 8-10, 1974 (Box-folder 67: 1-5)
      - Chapters 7-11, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 68: 1-7)
      - 1977-1980
        - Chapters 1-5 (Box-folder 69: 1-7)
        - Chapters 5-6 (Box-folder 70: 1-4)
        - Chapter 6 (Box-folder 71: 1-5)
        - Chapters 7-9 (Box-folder 72: 1-6)
        - Chapters 9-10 (Box-folder 73: 1-4)
        - Chapter 11 (Box-folder 74: 1)
        - Chapters 8-10 (corrections) (Box-folder 74: 2)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 74: 3-5)
    - Correspondence
      - Gordon, Robert J., 1976 (Box-folder 74: 6)
      - Karni, Edi, 1977 (Box-folder 74: 7)
      - Schwartz, Anna J., 1967-1977 (Box-folder 74: 8)
      - Siegel, Jeremy J., 1977 (Box-folder 74: 9)
  - "The Budget Standoff: Its Implications for the Economy," speech, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford, California, typescript, 1982 May 14 (Box-folder 74: 10)
- Academic Career, 1939-1976 (Boxes 75-80)
  Course material, examination records, memoranda, minutes, proposals, studies, and correspondence, arranged chronologically by university.
  - Columbia University, Economics Ub-171, "Structure of Neo-Classical Economics," reading assignments and lecture notes, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1940-1941
    - Economics b114, bibliography (Box-folder 75: 2)
    - Economics 121, examination questions (Box-folder 75: 3)
    - Economics 129, "Statistical Economics," examination questions (Box-folder 75: 4)
    - Economics 176, "Business Cycles," lecture notes, examination questions, and student papers (Box-folder 75: 5)
    - Economics 201, syllabus (Box-folder 75: 6)
    - Economics 232, "Seminar in Income and Wealth," notes and reading assignments (Box-folder 75: 7)
  - United States Department of Agriculture Graduate School, Washington, D.C., "Statistical Analysis of Economic and Social Problems,", 1942
    - Background material (Box-folder 75: 8)
    - Lecture notes, examination questions, and correspondence (Box-folder 75: 9)
  - University of Minnesota, 1945-1946
    - B.A. 70, "Statistics Survey," course outlines, notes, examination questions, and student paper (Box-folder 75: 10)
    - B.A. 101, syllabus (Box-folder 75: 11)
    - B.A. 102, "Advanced General Economics," assignments (Box-folder 75: 12)
    - B.A. 112, "Business Statistics," lecture notes and examination questions (Box-folder 75: 13)
  - University of Chicago, 1946-1976
    - Course material, 1946-1972
      Reading assignments, lecture notes, problems, examination questions, grade sheets, course descriptions, syllabi.
      - Unidentified (Box-folder 76: 1)
      - "Economic Theory" (Box-folder 76: 2)
      - "Seminar on Business Cycles" (Box-folder 76: 3)
      - Economics 7 (Box-folder 76: 4)
      - Economics 129, "Statistical Economics" (Box-folder 76: 5)
      - Economics 150 (Box-folder 76: 6)
      - Economics 208, "Production and Distribution" (Box-folder 76: 7)
      - Economics 230 (Box-folder 76: 8)
      - Economics 300A (Box-folder 76: 9)
      - Economics 300B (Box-folder 76: 10)
      - Economics 300A and 300B (Box-folder 77: 1)
      - Economics 301 (Box-folder 77: 2)
      - Economics 302 (Box-folder 77: 3)
      - Economics 301 and 302 (Box-folder 77: 4)
      - Economics 305 (Box-folder 77: 5)
      - Economics 311 (Box-folder 77: 6)
      - Economics 330, "Money" (Box-folder 77: 7)
      - Economics 331, "Banking Theory and Monetary Policy" (also called "Money") (Box-folder 77: 8)
      - Economics 332
        - General (Box-folder 77: 9)
        - Lectures 1-6 (Box-folder 77: 10)
        - Lectures 7-12 (Box-folder 77: 11)
        - Lectures 13-16 (Box-folder 77: 12)
      - Economics 334 (Box-folder 78: 1)
      - Economics 335 (Box-folder 78: 2)
      - Economics 432, "Seminar in Monetary Dynamics" (Box-folder 78: 3-4)
      - Economics 496, "Selected Topics in Contemporary Economic Problems" (Box-folder 78: 5)
    - Memoranda by Milton Friedman
      - "A Tentative Proposal for Corporate Reform and Research Required for Judging It,", undated (Box-folder 78: 6)
      - "Proposed Study of Faculty Cost of Living,", 1948 December 1 (Box-folder 78: 7)
        Includes comments from Hazel Kyrk.
      - "Proposed Study of Consumption and Income Distribution,", 1956 March 13 (Box-folder 78: 8)
        Includes correspondence with the Rockefeller Foundation.
    - Minutes
      Includes memoranda and correspondence.
      - Curriculum Committee
        - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 78: 9-10)
        - 1950 (Box-folder 78: 11)
      - Economics Department
        - 1946-1949 (Box-folder 79: 1)
        - 1949-1953 (Box-folder 79: 2)
        - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 79: 3)
      - Executive Committee of the Free Market Study, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 79: 4)
      - Ph.D. Thesis Outlines and Requirements Committee, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 79: 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 79: 6)
    - Student doctoral theses (under the direction of Milton Friedman) and papers (under the direction of other professors) (Box-folder 80: 1)